ASHUR KANWAL

65 Claret, Grangemouth FK39LS Scotland Mobile: 07397325523, Email: ashurkanwal@yahoo.com Resume Web: <u>ashur-k.github.io/Resume-Web-Ashur/</u> GitHub Link: github.com/ashur-k

Full Stack Web Developer, qualified with a Diploma in Software Development from Code Institute (CI) and software engineering degree from Pakistan institute of management science and technology (PIMSAT). Strong understanding of object-oriented programming and 18 months experience of web-development. I am developing my skills set to be a great asset for my employer.

CORE SKILLS:

Frontend:	Backends:
HTML CSS Sass JavaScript jQuery AJAX	Python Flask Django Django Allauth
React React-redux	Django-Rest-Framework
UI Frameworks:	Databases:
Bootstrap Materializecss React-bootstrap font-awesome Chart-JS	SQL Mongodb PostgreSQL Db-sqlite3
APIS Implemented:	Payment Systems:
Google-Maps Email-JS GitHub API Rapid	PayPal (implemented in react project) Stripe
Covid-Data API	(implemented many times)
Testing and Development:	Amazon Web Services:
Balsamiq wireframes Gitpod VS-code Postman pgAdmin drawSql	S3 IAM RDS
Source Control:	Hosting:
GitHub	GitHub Heroku

WORK HISTORY

FINISHED AND HOSTED PROJECTS:

PROJECT 1 - TITLE: PROSHOP (FEB-2021 - APRIL-2021)

Fully functional e-commerce site with product-search, sort, add-to-bag and order-checkout features. Products with its image. User account, can maintain his/her profile, view order history and rate and comment products. PayPal payment system, Heroku and Amazon Web Services RDS, S3, and IAM services for hosting.

Frameworks and languages: React | Axios | React-redux | react-bootstrap | Sqlite3 | PostgreSQL | Django rest framework | Postman.

 $\textbf{Site \& GitHub Links:} \ \underline{\text{https://proshop-ash.herokuapp.com/\#/}} \ | \ \underline{\text{https://github.com/ashur-k/proshop-ash.herokuapp.com/\#/}} \ | \ \underline{\text{https://github.com/ashur-k/proshop-ash.herokuapp.com/}} \ | \ \underline{\text{https://github.com/ashur-k/proshop-ash.herokuapp.com/}} \ | \ \underline{\text{https://github.com/ashur-k/proshop-ash.herokuapp.com/}} \ | \ \underline{\text$

PROJECT 2 - TITLE: RR-CLOTH (SEP 2020 - DEC-2020)

Fully functional e-commerce site with product-search, sort, add-to-bag and order-checkout features. Products with its color, size variants and an image gallery. The User can maintain his/her user profile, view order history and rate and comment product. Stripe payment system with stripe webhooks to provide an efficient payment system for the user. Heroku/ Heroku-Postgresql and Amazon Web Services for hosting.

Frameworks and languages: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Sqlite3, PostgreSQL, Django/Python.

Site & GitHub Links: rr-cloth.herokuapp.com/|github.com/ashur-k/RR-Clothes

PROJECT 3 - TITLE: CAR SALES SHOWROOM (APRIL-2020 TO JULY-2020)

Comprehensively built website in Flask Python, User can view cars and book appointments for a test drive. The site administrator has a login/logout system to maintain car records, user appointments and systematically organize bookings for test drives.

Frameworks and languages: HTML, CSS, Materializecss, JavaScript, jQuery, MongoDB and Flask/Python.

Site & GitHub Links: car-sales-showroom.herokuapp.com/index | github.com/ashur-k/CI-MS3-Car-Showroom.

Links, previews and details for these and other projects are provided at my resume site:		
Project 4 – Boutique-ado	July - 2020 to August - 2020	
Project 5 - Title: Covid-19 Pandemic	Jan - 2020 to March - 2020	
Project 6 - Title: Bend River Media	Nov - 2020 to Dec - 2019	
Commercial and voluntary Projects:		
Project 1 - Title: Church Site https://kirk-of-the-holy-rood-church and media queries are not completed	n.herokuapp.com/ In Testing Phase Jan-2021- present	
Project 1 - Title: Church Site https://jacxx-productions.herokuapp instructions from client	o.com/ In Testing Phase waiting for March-2021- present	
Project 3 - Title: HAHZ Whole Sale Ecommerce Site	April-2021 – present	

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE:

Stockton Baptist Church member of audio / visual team	2011 - 2019
IT teacher and administrator	2007 - 2010
Parttime business, running computer gaming hub	2007 - 2010
Parttime hardware software repair troubleshooting	2007 - 2010
Assistant to manager garment company	2005 - 2007
Assistant School Teacher	2001 - 2005

EDUCATION

Software Development diploma CI. Accredited by the Napier university, Edinburgh	2019 - 2020
BTEC from Riverside college in Stockton on Tees England	2011 - 2013
First-Line Manager diploma from Riverside college in Stockton on Tees England	2011 - 2012
ITQ Computer Graphics from Riverside college in Stockton on Tees England	2011 - 2012
BSC Information Technology from PIMSAT	2001 - 2005
A-Levels (Maths, Physics, Organic and inorganic Chemistry, English)	1999 - 2000
O-Levels (Biology, Maths, Physics, Chemistry, English)	1998 - 1999

Udemy Courses

Django with React and Ecommerce site - 84 Lectures 18 hours	100% completed
Complete React Developer - 366 lectures 40 hours	40% completed
UI/UX Design - 37 lectures 2 hours	46% completed

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Hobbies: Playing Cricket, Gym, playing playstation, reading

UK Immigration Status: Full time work permission don't require visa or sponsorship

References: I can provide references when asked